A Guide to the Robert James Sullivan Jr. Papers, ca. 1930-2013: SC 0003
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Series 4: Scrapbooks and Newspaper, 1945-2012
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, January 2003 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, February 2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, March 2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, April 2003 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, May 2003 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, June 2003 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, July 2003 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, August 2003 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, September 2003 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, October 2003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, November 2003 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, December 2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, January 2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, February 2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, March 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, April 2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, May 2004 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, June 2004 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, July 2004 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, August 2004 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, September 2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, October 2004 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, November 2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, December 2004 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, January 2005 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, February 2005 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, March 2005 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, April 2005 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, May 2005 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, June 2005 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, July 2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, August 2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, September 2005, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, October 2005 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, November 2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Daily News-Record, December 2005 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings – Harrisonburg Growth, 2006-2012 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Survey of Selected Newspaper Headlines from the Harrisonburg Planning Scrapbooks, 1950s-1990s, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Survey of Selected Newspaper Headlines from the Harrisonburg Planning Commission Scrapbooks, 1965-1983, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Survey of Selected Newspaper Headlines from the Harrisonburg Planning Commission Scrapbooks, 1984-2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series 5: Maps, 1958-1993
  The maps series contains maps that document areas of Harrisonburg slated for urban renewal, hand-drawn maps created by Sullivan that show the growth of Harrisonburg over time, and miscellaneous maps of Harrrisonburg and Rockingham County from various sources. Text within brackets [ ] indicates additional descriptive information added by the archivist. Each map has been numbered on the back in the bottom right corner.
  - Urban Renewal Project Maps - VA R-4 and Project VA R-16, 1958-1967, undated (Mapcase 3, Drawer 8, Folder 1)
    - Map 1: Present Zoning (1958) Northeast Harrisonburg Urban Renewal Area, 1958
    - Map 2: Northeast Harrisonburg Land Use (1958), 1958
    - Map 3: [Broad Street, Mason Street, N. Main Street] Northeast Harrisonburg Urban Renewal Area, August 24, 1960
    - Map 4: Street Adjustment Plan Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg, Virginia, November 17, 1960
    - Map 5: Project Area Map Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg, Virginia, Wolfe Street Area, April 20, 1960
    - Map 6: Disposition Plan Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg, Virginia, Wolfe Street Urban Renewal Area, January 1961
    - Map 7: Site Improvement Plan, Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg Virginia, Wolfe Street Urban Renewal Area, January 1961
    - Map 8: Boundary Map, Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg Virginia, Wolfe Street Urban Renewal Area, January 12, 1961
    - Map 9: Land Acquisition Plan, Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg, Virginia, January 12, 1961
    - Map 10: Land Use Map, Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg, Virginia, Wolfe Street Area, January 12, 1961
    - Map 11: [Urban Renewal Map] This description made in July 1967, City Planning Office, R.J. Sullivan Jr., Director, 1967
    - Map 12: [Broad Street, E. Gay St.] Northeast Harrisonburg Urban Renewal Area, Harrisonburg, Virginia, undated
    - Map 13: [N. Mason St, Rock St.] Proposed Zoning, Northeast Harrisonburg Urban Renewal Area, Harrisonburg, Virginia, undated
    - Map 14: [Effinger Street, Broad St] Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Property Map Northeast Harrisonburg, undated
    - Map 15: Harrisonburg Planning Commission Proposed Street Intersection Channelization and Traffic Signal Installation, North Main & North Mason, Harrisonburg, VA, undated
    - Map 16: Map No. R-203 Site Clearance Northeast Harrisonburg Urban Renewal Project No.VA-R-4, Harrisonburg, Virginia, undated
    - Map 17: [N. Mason, E. Rock St.] Harrisonburg Redevelopment and Housing Authority, undated
    - Map 18: [Broad St., Rock St.] Northeast Harrisonburg Land Values, Urban Renewal Area, Harrisonburg, Virginia, undated
    - Map 19: [Broad St., Rock St.] Property Map Northeast Harrisonburg Urban Renewal Area, undated
    - Map 20: Proposed Street Intersection Channelization and Traffic Signal Installation, N. Main – N. Mason – E. Johnson, Harrisonburg, VA, undated
    - Map 21: Streets, Curb & Gutter and Sidewalk, Northeast Harrisonburg Urban Renewal Area, undated
    - Map 22: [Broad St., E. Rock St.] Street Adjustment Plan, Harrisonburg Redevelopment & Housing Authority, Harrisonburg, VA, undated
    - Map 23: Urban Renewal Poster, undated
  - Hand-drawn Maps, 1958-1980, undated (Mapcase 3, Drawer 8, Folder 2)
    - Map 24: "Future Harrisonburg" by Bob Sullivan, August 1958
    - Map 25: Existing Land Use in Harrisonburg, Va., 1966
    - Map 26: A Map of Thomas Harrison's Town of Harrisonburg Virginia 1780, January 1980
    - Map 27: Harrisonburg, 100 Years Ago, January 1980
    - Map 28: Harrisonburg with By-pass, new street traffic-plan & annexation, undated
  - Harrisonburg and Rockingham County Maps, 1981-1993, undated (Mapcase 3, Drawer 8, Folder 3)
    - Map 29: Map of Harrisonburg, Virginia and Environs / Rockingham County, Virginia, compiled at James Madison University Cartography Lab, 1981
    - Map 30: Map of Harrisonburg Virginia and Environs, Harrisonburg-Rockingham Chamber of Commerce, May 1985
    - Map 31-33: Harrisonburg, Virginia and Vicinity—Zoning Map, compiled at the James Madison University Geography Lab, 1988
    - Map 34: Map of Harrisonburg Virginia and Environs, 1983-1993
    - Map 35: Map of Harrisonburg and Rockingham County, Virginia, issued by Old Dominion Realty, Inc., undated
    - Map 36: Harrisonburg, Virginia, undated
    - Map 37: Map of Harrisonburg Virginia 1916, revised to 1936, undated
    - Map 38: Rockingham County, Virginia, undated
- Series 6: Photographs and Slides, ca. 1930-2006
  Arranged into two subseries: Photographs, ca. 1930-2006, undated, and Slides, ca. 1965-1988. Arranged chronologically within the photographs subseries, and alphabetically by slide grouping title in the slides subseries.
  - Subseries 6.1: Photographs, ca. 1930-2006
    Subseries 6.1: Photographs, ca. 1930-2006, contains images of Harrisonburg from ca. 1930-2006. Images document the areas of Harrisonburg targeted for urban renewal in the 1960s, buildings and other features of downtown Harrisonburg from the 1960s-early 2000s, historic buildings in Harrisonburg, and some images of Harrisonburg High School football. Also included are images of students in classes taught by Sullivan from 1990-2006, as well as images from the walking tours that he conducted with his students. Items identified as photo albums in the inventory below were removed from their original albums and foldered individually with corresponding captions as folder titles.
    - Panoramic view of Harrisonburg-Looking east from top of Annie Burke Good hill on south side of West Market Street, ca. 1930 (Mapcase 3, Drawer 8, Folder 4)
    - Daily News Record Oct. 1, 1959 Flooding photos and article, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Northwest and Southeast "Slums", ca. 1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Photos, ca. 1960-2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Some of Harrisonburg's historic structures June 1976, 1963, 1967, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Old Photographs: Harrisonburg [includes view of Court Square from 1890s], ca. 1965, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Old Photographs: Harrisonburg Schools, ca. 1965, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Downtown, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Photographs: Harrisonburg Public Housing, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - High Street widening 1968-1969 Before and After (folder 1 of 2), 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - High Street widening 1968-1969 Before and After (folder 2 of 2), 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 1969 High Street Widening Project, 1966-1969, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Photographs Harrisonburg, June 1969 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Photograph: Planning Commission, December 1972 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Downtown Harrisonburg sidewalk beautification project [photos], 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Downtown Harrisonburg sidewalk beautification project [negatives], 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Photographs and Negatives "Planning Director Sullivan", ca. 1980 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Photos and Negatives: Construction, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Aerial views of Downtown Harrisonburg July 1984 and Flood in Downtown- early 2000s, 1984, ca. 2000 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - VCPA Conference Photographs May 18-20, 1986, 1986, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Southeast, 1988, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - JMU Classes - Walking Tours, 1990, 2001-2006, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Blessed Sacrament Church [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - City-County Jail & the Old County Jail [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 1999, 2004, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - County Office Building (The National Bank) [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Hardesty Higgins House [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 2001, 2006, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Harrisonburg Electric Commission West Bruce Street [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Harrisonburg High School [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 2003, 2005, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Harrisonburg Police Station South Liberty Street [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 1999, 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Harrisonburg Public Safety Building, North Main Street [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Harrisonburg School Board Office [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Hose Co. # 4 East Rock Street [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Judicial Center West Court Square [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Massanutten Regional Library [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 1999-2003, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Municipal Building [Photo Album – 1995-2006, undated], 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Old Harrisonburg Post Office, 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Polly Lineweaver Apartments North Main Street, 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Rockingham County Administration Center, 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Rockingham County Court House, 1995-2006, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Rockingham Memorial Hospital, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Social Services & Health Department Building, 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Warren-Sipe House Quilt Museum, 2001, 2004, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - World War One Monument South Main - South Liberty, 2004, 2006, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - West Market Street Widening, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Northwest, 1999-2001, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Downtown, 1999-2005 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Northeast, 1999-2006 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Photo Album - Harrisonburg Buildings, ca. 2000 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Harrisonburg "City Hall" Bryan Mabry, Harrisonburg School Board Office, VA Quilt Museum, Massanutten Regional Library, Rockingham County Office Building, Rockingham County Court House, Rockingham-Harrisonburg Judicial Center, Rockingham-Harrisonburg Dept. of Health and Social Services, J. R. Lineweaver Apartments, Harrisonburg Fire Station #4, VA Dept. of Taxation Office, ABC Store, Rockingham Co. Government Administration Center, Rockingham Harrisonburg Judicial Center, Harrisonburg Electric Commission, Court House Clock Tower
    - Harrisonburg photos (various places) from flight over Harrisonburg with Jeff Harris - also Piper Cubs, etc., June 2001, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Harrisonburg High School 2001 State Football Champions at Court Square, December 2001 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Photographs: HHS Football, HHS Baseball ca 1920, and cemeteries, 2002-2006 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Harrisonburg High School and Dukes Plaza, 1999-2005, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Aerial Photographs of Harrisonburg, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Courthouse, Morrison photograph, late 1800s, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - 1890s Harrisonburg, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Harrisonburg Post Office/Federal Building Mural, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Kavanaugh Hotel, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Polsci and Geography photo, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Slum Photographs Harrisonburg VA, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Subseries 6.2: Slides, ca. 1965-1988
    All images within the Slides subseries have been digitized and are available to view within JMU Scholarly Commons (https://commons.lib.jmu.edu/rjs/). Each individual grouping is also listed and linked in the inventory below. The slides are arranged topically based on the original arrangement created by Sullivan and are listed alphabetically in the inventory below. Sullivan wrote additional information that describes the images onto most slides in the collection. That descriptive information is listed as the title when viewing the images within JMU Scholarly Commons. Most images in the slides subseries document Harrisonburg and the surrounding area from the 1960s-1980s. Other content includes images of Reston, VA, and Durham, NC that feature housing complexes and downtown areas. Please note that images of Harrisonburg are found within the grouping labeled as "Durham, NC," as well as in the grouping titled "non-H'burg."
    - 1978, 1979, and Spring 1980 (showing part of the Bicentennial Parade- H'burg's 200th birthday), 1978-1980 (Box OV 2)
    - Court Square (after landscaping), 1976-1977 (Box OV 2)
    - Downtown Photos, Various Items 1960s, 70s, 80s, 1966-1985, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Durham, NC Street Plantings and Downtown Beautification, 1976 (Box OV 2)
    - Fall '79, Dry River Dam, '83, Mixed views etc., 1966-1988 (Box OV 2)
    - Historical structures and churches, schools and parks, JMU and EMC, 1967-1988, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Housing— various types and situations, 1966-1988, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Industries, Railroad Pollution Scenes…City Facilities- parking lots, fire stations, police station, HEC; "Miscellaneous", 1966-1986, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Late 1960s, ca. 1965-ca. 1975 (Box OV 2)
    - May-July, 1980 (Box OV 2)
    - Non-H'burg 1968-88, 1968-1988, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Old Town, 1988, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Pee Wee Football and Handley HS, 1978-1984 (Box OV 2)
    - Pre Plan City, 1983, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Reston, VA, Columbia, MD, Green Run, VA Beach, 1970-1972 (Box OV 2)
    - Slum slides, 1967-1974 (Box OV 2)
    - Steam plant pictures, Winter 1981-1982, Spring & Summer 1982, 1981-1982, undated (Box OV 2)
    - Street construction projects, 1966-1981 (Box OV 2)